<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TUI | Unnikrishnan R</title>
    <link>/tags/tui/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/tui/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>TUI</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Unnikrishnan R - 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 17:03:19 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>TUI</title>
      <link>/tags/tui/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tangible Interface for Toilet Location Surveying</title>
      <link>/project/tangibletoilet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 17:03:19 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/tangibletoilet/</guid>
      <description>





&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/tangibletoilet.jpg&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/tangibletoilet.jpg&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;There are two tangible objects, one representing a toilet and the other the soak pit. AR tags placed on top enable tracking of the objects using an overhead camera. Both control the poses of their virtual avatars on the laptop&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;





&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/tan1.gif&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/tan1.gif&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;The facilitator guides the study participant (both hail from the same village) on using the system&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/tan2.gif&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/tan2.gif&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Students control the position/orientation of the tangible toilet/soak pit under various scenarios&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;







&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/tan3.gif&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/tan3.gif&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;The TUI moves intot the background and becomes an enabler of deeper conversations around sanitation between the participants&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tangible Interface for Carpentry Planning Skills</title>
      <link>/project/carpentrytui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 10:51:21 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/carpentrytui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of a collaboration with EPFL&amp;rsquo;s Chili Labs, I developed a tangible interface for training carpenters in optimizing wood cut planning. Optimal arrangement of woodcut layout when done manually, faces two challenges, one being that the apprentice carpenter does not get real time feedback on how efficient their arrangement is and the second being that most are not motivated enough to do such a task (perhaps because of the cognitive load). From a pedagogical view, such a problem can be tackled with the help of elements of gamification, like giving real time feedback on performance, leaderboards for identifying the best performers (in the classroom or workplace) and additional features that enables instructors or supervisors to add and customize scenarios of their choosing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This problem of optimization of material use has been tackled by the textile, sheet metal cutting
and carpentry cutting machine industries for many decades and is still an active area of research in the fields of computational geometry and operations research. In a way the goal of
this project is to translate this kind of “computational” efficiency found in the automation industry into human workers which could prove useful in developing nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem of optimizing the arrangement of the component pieces needed to be made quantifiable (for the scoring to work) while reflecting real world usefulness as well. So it was recharacterized as a problem of finding the Maximum Empty (axis-parallel) Rectangle (MER)
that can be fit into the empty space remaining in the workpiece after arranging the component
pieces. Though in the real world, one would not get neat rectangular pieces as leftover from the
cutting process, by considering the MER we can reasonably quantify the leftover material’s
utility for future use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;shape--scenario-editors&#34;&gt;Shape &amp;amp; Scenario Editors&lt;/h3&gt;






&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/carp2.png&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/carp2.png&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Shape editor&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​The shape editor lets the instructor add contour information of the shape of each wood piece into the system, which is mapped to the chilitag placed on the piece. The contour data is stored into a YML file as (x,y) offsets from the position of the chilitag’s center. Image processing tasks here were implemented using OpenCV. ​The scenario module lets the instructor associate a group of shapes to a scenario using their associated AR tags. This helps in providing the scoring metrics and a simple hint system as shown below.&lt;/p&gt;






&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/carp1.png&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/carp1.png&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Bending a square shape&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;game&#34;&gt;Game&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game ​: The objective of the game is to maximize the size of the Maximum Empty Rectangle (MER) that can be formed from the area left empty. Two interfaces were implemented for visualizing the MER, one in a virtual representation of the workpieces (using Unity3D) and the other by overlaying the MER on top of the live video stream itself. The ​CGAL​ library was used to find the MER.&lt;/p&gt;






&lt;figure&gt;

  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;/img/carp3.png&#34; &gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/carp3.png&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;A near optimal solution for this collection of shapes&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
